Finding Aid for the Ralph John Slosser Papers PASC.0164
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ralph John Slosser papers
circa 1920-circa 1967
UCLA Library Special Collections
Slosser, Ralph John
PASC.0164
5.0 Linear Feet (11 boxes)
Ralph Slosser was a production manager and assistant director. The collection consists of screenplays, television scripts, photographs, and production material related to Slosser's career.
11 boxes (5 linear ft.)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mr. John Slosser, 1980.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9929769263606533
Biography
There is little biographical information about John Ralph Slosser. Slosser, who is generally credited as Ralph Slosser, was a production manager and director, often in the position of assistant director. He worked with directors such as Thor Brooks, Charles Lamont, Frank McDonald, King Vidor, and Jean Yarbrough, among others. Among his film credits are Gone with the Wind, Our Miss Brooks, and Slave Girl. His television credits include The Cisco Kid, Meet Corliss Archer, Mr. &amp and Mrs. North, and others.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of screenplays, television scripts, photographs, and production material related to the career of director, Ralph Slosser. Includes material for a number of television and film productions. The film projects represented inlcude Gone with the Wind (1939), The Oregon Trail (1959), Phantom of the Opera (1925), Ride, Ryder, Ride!(1949), Scarface (1932), Young Jesse James (1960), The Well(1951) and others. Television projects represented include Adventures of Ozzie and Harriet, Arts Linkletter's House Party, Cisco Kid, Duffy of San Quentin, and others.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Motion Picutre Projects
Television Projects
Photographs
Motion picture producers and directors -- Archives.; Slosser, Ralph John -- Archives
- Photographs
  - Signed photographs (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Scope and Content Note
    Photographs inscribed to Ralph Slosser; many signatures hard to decipher. Includes Douglas Fairbanks, Mary Pickford, Marjorie Daw, WH Bainbridge, and Raymond Hatton, among others. 43 total, 19 unidentified.
  - Babe Ruth and Joe DiMaggio, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Scope and Contentl note
    Two photographs. 8x10. No dates.
  - Early Model Automobiles, circa 1922 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Scope and Content note
    IOWA GARAGE RENTAL CAR, Pasadena, CA. 1920s cars. Items dated 1922. 20 total.
- Film Projects
  - PUBLICITY PHOTOGRAPHS (Box 11, Folder 1)
    The Barrier (1937 Paramount), Fatal Holiday (1938), Maria Rosa (1923), River Boat Mystery (1944 Universal), and White Tiger (Universal 1923). 20 total, 5 unidentified.
  - PUBLICITY PHOTOGRAPHS (Box 11, Folder 9)
    General note
    8x10, mostly for silent films. 13 total, 3 unidentified.
  - PUBLICITY PHOTOGRAPHS (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Various film productions, most are silent films (3x5 and 4x6). 25 total, 3 unidentified.
  - BARRIER (THE) (1937 PARAMOUNT) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Final screenplay by Bernard Schubert. Dated, 06/10/37.
  - BRUSHFIRE (1962 PARAMOUNT) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Screenplay by Irwin R. Blacker. Dated 06/09/61. Annotated.
  - BUBBLE (THE) (1967 ARCH OBLER) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Final screenplay by Arch Obler. No date. Annotated. 3D film.
  - BULLWHIP (1958 ALLIED ARTISTS) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Also known as Bull-Whipped. Final screenplay by Adele Buffington. Dated 10/23/57.
  - CALYPSO JOE (1957 ALLIED ARTISTS) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Screenplay by Edward and Mildred Dein. Dated 03/07/57.
  - CHAINED FOR LIFE (1950 CLASSIC FILMS) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Screenplay by Sam Neuman and Nat Tanchuck. Annotated. No date. Includes production materials.
  - CHAMPAGNE FOR CAESAR (1950 UNITED ARTISTS) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Screenplay by Hans Jacoby and Fred Brady. Dated 08/18/49. Annotated. Includes production materials.
  - CLAMBAKE (1967 UNITED ARTISTS) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Screenplay by Arthur Brown, Jr. Dated 12/14/66. Annotated. Film stars Elvis Presley.
  - DIARY OF FATE (THE) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Screenplay by Donn Hornung. Unproduced film. Script marked Property of Ralph Slosser.
  - DOUBLE DEAL (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Screenplay. No author, no date. Annotated. Enclosed is statement of payment to Ralph Slosser for work on the film. Statement dated 10/24/39.
  - DUEL IN THE CITY (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Also known as The High Powered Rifle. Screenplay. No author. Dated 02/15/60. Annotated. Ralph Slosser, assistant director.
  - ETERNAL THREE (1923 GOLDWYN) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Script for silent film. No date, no author. A Marshall Neilan Production.
  - FIRST LEGION (THE) (1951 UNITED ARTISTS) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Screenplay by Emmet Lavery. Dated 05/05/50. Annotated. Includes production materials.
  - FRONTIER GAL (1945 UNIVERSAL) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Screenplay by Michael Fessier and Ernest Pagano. Dated 04/18/45. Annotated. Includes production materials.
  - FURY OF THE JUNGLE (1934 COLUMBIA) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Screenplay by Ethel Hill and Dore Schary. No date.
  - GONE WITH THE WIND (1939 MGM) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Production materials. Dated 03/29/39.
  - GONE WITH THE WIND (1939 MGM) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Screenplay by Sidney Howard and Oliver H.P. Garrett. Dated 01/18/39.
  - GONE WITH THE WIND (1939 MGM) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Shooting script. Dated 03/23/39.
  - GUN HAWK (THE) (1963 ALLIED ARTISTS) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Screenplay by Jo Heims. Dated 09/27/62. Includes production materials.
  - GUN TOWN (1946 UNIVERSAL) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Screenplay by William Lively. Dated 08/24/45. Annotated. Includes production materials. Assistant Director, Ralph Slosser.
  - HEADING FOR HEAVEN (1947 Eagle-Lion) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Production materials. No date. Assistant director, Ralph Slosser.
  - LEGION OF THE DOOMED (1958 ALLIED ARTISTS) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Also known as Legion of the Damned. Screenplay by Tom Hubbard and Fred Eggers. Annotated. Includes production materials. Assistant Director, Ralph Slosser.
  - LONESOME LADIES (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Production materials for unproduced film. No date. Assistant director, Ralph Slosser.
  - LOUIS ARMSTRONG MUSICALS (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Theatrical shorts. Includes: I'll be Glad When You're Dead You Rascal You (04/17/42), When It's Sleepy Time Down South (04/18/42), and Shine (04/18/42).
  - MATA HARI (1931 MGM) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Screenplay by Benjamin Glazer. German and English. No date. Includes production materials.
  - NEXT TIME WE LOVE (1936 UNIVERSAL) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Also known as Next Time We Live. Screenplay by Ursula Parrott. Dated 04/05/35. Annotated.
  - OPEN SECRET (1948 MARATHON) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Screenplay by Henry Blankfort and Max Wilk. Annotated. Includes production materials.
  - OREGON TRAIL (THE) (1959 FOX) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Production materials.
  - OREGON TRAIL (THE) (1959 FOX) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Screenplay by Lou Vittes. Dated 05/22/59.
  - OUR DAILY BREAD (1934 UNITED ARTISTS) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Production materials and music. Includes memo from Slosser. No date.
  - OUR MISS BROOKS (1956 WARNER BROTHERS) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Production materials. Includes story board. No date.
  - PHANTOM OF THE OPERA (1925 UNIVERSAL) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Set drawings by Ben Carre. 8x10. Dated 1925. 20 drawings total.
  - PHANTOM OF THE OPERA (1925 UNIVERSAL) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Set stills, 8x10. Related to the set drawings. No date. 32 photographs total.
  - PORTRAIT OF A MOBSTER (1961 WARNER BROTHERS) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Screenplay by Howard Brown. Dated 11/09/60. Annotated. Includes production materials.
  - RIDE, RYDER, RIDE! (1949 EQUITY) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Serial. Script by Paul Franklin. Dated September, 1948. Broken into chapters.
  - RIDE, RYDER, RIDE! (1949 EQUITY) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    West of Devil's Hole. Chapter 3. Script by Paul Franklin and Jerry Thomas. Serial.
  - ROYAL MOUNTED RIDES AGAIN (THE) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Script for thirteen chapter serial by M.B. Cox. Dated 07/09/45.
  - SCANDAL INC (1956 REPUBLIC) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Screenplay by Milton K Mann. Annotated. No date. Includes production materials.
  - SCARFACE (1932 United Artists) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Interoffice Memos. No date.
  - SCARFACE (1932 UNITED ARTISTS) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - SCARFACE (1932 UNITED ARTISTS) (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Publicity photographs. 8x10. Labeled on back with description of scene. 16 total, 2 autographed to Ralph Slosser.
  - SCARFACE (1932 UNITED ARTISTS) (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Set photographs. 8x10. Interiors and exteriors. 87 total.
  - SECRET DOOR (1964 ALLIED ARTISTS) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Also known as Now It Can Be Told. Screenplay by Charles Martin. Dated 05/27/58.
  - SEEING IT THROUGH (1920) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Production materials. Directed by Claude H. Mitchell. No date. Assistant director, Ralph Slosser.
  - SHADOW OF A DOUBT (1943 UNIVERSAL) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Screenplay by Thorton Wilder. Dated 07/28/42. Includes production materials.
  - SHANGHAI GESTURE (1941 UNITED ARTISTS) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Screenplay by Karl Vollmoeller, Geza Herczeg, James Cain and Jules Furthman. Annotated. No date.
  - SLAVE GIRL (1947 UNIVERSAL) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Also known as Tripoli. Screenplay by Michael Fessier and Ernest Pagano. Dated 08/09/46. Annotated. Includes production materials.
  - SNAFU (Box 7, Folder 6)
    War Department. Screenplay for Fighting Man series War Department training films. Dated 11/09/43. Annotated by Ralph Slosser.
  - SPIRIT OF ST LOUIS (1957 WARNER BROTHERS) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Production materials. Dated 07/09/55.
  - STELLA MARIS (1925) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Screenplay from the novel by William J Locks. Directed by Charles J. Brabin. Dated 06/09/25. Includes production materials.
  - STRAIGHT FROM PARIS (1921) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Screenplay by Sada Cowan. No date.
  - SWEET CHARITY (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Also known at The Big Tip Off or Twighligh Alley. Screenplay by Steve Fisher. Dated 11/29/54. Annotated. Includes production materials. Assistant Director, Ralph Slosser.
  - WELL (THE) (1951 UNITED ARTISTS) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - WELL (THE) (1951 UNITED ARTISTS) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Screenplay by Russell Rouse and Clarence Greens. Dated 09/07/50. Annotated.
  - WINNER'S CIRCLE (1948 FOX) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Screenplay by Howard J. Green. No date. Annotated. Includes production materials.
  - WOMEN OF PITCAIRN ISLAND (1957 FOX) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Production materials. Assistant director, Ralph Slosser.
  - WOMEN OF PITCAIRN ISLAND (THE) (1957 FOX) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg. Dated 07/20/56. Annotated.
  - YOUNG JESSE JAMES (1960 FOX) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Production materials. Dated 11/11/59.
- Television Projects
  - ADVENTURES OF OZZIE AND HARRIET (THE) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Father's Night at the Fraternity. Script and production materials. No author. No date. Aired on ABC, 1952-1966.
  - ARREST AND TRIAL (Box 9, Folder 2)
    The Best There Is. Script by Herb Meadow. Dated 12/30/63. Series aired on ABC from 1963-1964.
  - ART LINKLETTER'S HOUSE PARTY (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Show #2051, aired 07/18/60. Show #2054, aired 07/21/60. Nightly show on CBS.
  - BEVERLY HILLBILLIES (THE) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    The Buggy. Show #123. Script by Paul Henning and Mark Tuttle. Dated 11/12/65. Annotated. Aired on CBS, 1962-1971.
  - BIRTH OF A SONG (THE) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Scripts for nine episodes. Includes production materials.
  - CISCO KID (THE) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Two scripts for episodes. No episode titles. Both written by Barney A. Sarecky and Barry Cohon. Includes production materials.
  - DUFFY OF SAN QUENTIN (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Duffy of San Quentin, The Prosecutor, and The Nurse. Each script written by Walter Doniger. No dates.
  - EDDIE CANTOR COMEDY THEATER (Box 10, Folder 6)
    The Lieutenant Was No Gentleman. No author. No date.
  - GIRL FROM U.N.C.L.E. (THE) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    The Drublegratz Affair. Script by Boris Sobelman. Dated 11/08/66. Includes production materials. Aired on NBC, 1966-1967.
  - HEDDA HOPPER SELECTS THE BEST IN HOLLYWOOD (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Script for pilot. Dated 07/19/49. Includes production materials. Aired as an NBC special.
  - I LED THREE LIVES (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Episode 42B. Script by Stuart Jerome. Dated 07/07/54. Includes production materials. Syndicated only from 1953-1956, 117 episodes total.
  - MEET CORLISS ARCHER (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Also known as Corliss Archer. Includes - Business Woman (07/02/54), The Problem (07/19/54), and Test Your Mate (03/09/55). Aired on CBS, 1951-1952 and in syndication from 1954-1955.
  - MR. DISTRICT ATTORNEY (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Episode #51B. Script by Don Brinkley. Dated 03/01/55. Includes production materials. Aired on ABC, 1951-1952.
  - PABLO (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Rabbit with Horns. Pilot script for TV series. Dated 04/27/60.
  - SCIENCE FICTION THEATRE (Box 9, Folder 9)
    The Eyes of the Panther, episode 18B. Script by Doris Gilbert. Dated 05/13/55. Includes production materials. Syndicated only, 1955-1957. 78 episodes total.
  - THUNDERBIRDS (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Pilot. Script by Arthur Rowe. Dated 10/25/54.
  - TO THE DESSERT (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Script. Property of Edward Lewis Productions.
  - WAGON TRAIN (Box 8, Folder 4)
    The Sam Livingston Story. Script, dated 01/25/60. Series aired on NBC and ABC, 1957-1965.